Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Arab woman wearing a veil, looking to her left, wearing an intricate metal necklace and holding her left hand to her chest. On reverse side of ref274. 29.9 x 23.6 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Jewelry; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Women
- Two veiled women, carrying water pots on their heads, and a child seated on the ground in between them. On reverse side of ref273. 29.9 x 23.6 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Furnishings; Women; Pottery; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Egypt; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Children; Architecture
- A portrait of a woman wearing a veil and man wearing a military cap and mustache. 29.3 x 19.6 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Facial Hair; Uniforms; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Regional/National Dress; Military/Soldiers; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Men; Facial Hair; Group Portraits
- First Lieutenant Ismail Hakki angled to his left, wearing a suit, tie, striped white shirt and mustache. 25.9 x 20.3 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Turkish Writing; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Men; Ottoman Writing; Turkey; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography
- Man with small toothbrush mustache, wearing a three-piece suit and plaid tie. 29.6 x 19.5 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Facial Hair; Turkey; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Men
- 43 girls from Zapyon Greek High School, seated and standing around two long tables. 24.9 x 32.8 cm, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Girls; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Greek Writing
- Bosphorus. View from the Asian shore towards the opposite European shoe with the Rumelihisari Castle across the water. 25.9 x 33.4 cm, Circa 1870 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Boats/Ships; Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Roumeli Hissar Castle; Albumen Prints; Bosphorus; Landscapes
- Group of people standing in front of a mosque in Adapazari. An imam stands in front of the group leading the prayer. 25 x 33 cm, Circa 1890 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Armenian Writing; Adapazari, Turkey; Greek Writing; Mosques; Group Portraits; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Buildings
- Yedikule Fortress in Constantinople with grass in the foreground and a house in front of the fort. 27 x 33.1 cm., Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Forts/Castles; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- Walls and battlements of the Yedikule Fortress, with patches of grass in front. 27.1 x 33.2 cm., Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Forts/Castles; French Writing
- Bird's eye view of Bursa. 26.6 x 35 cm., Circa 1870 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Houses; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Albumen Prints; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Bursa, Turkey; French Writing
- Walls of Constantinople. 27.2 x 33 cm., Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Architecture; Forts/Castles
- Three men in front of the Fountain (sabil) of Sultan Ahmed III in the square outside the Topkapi Palace. 34 x 26 cm., 1860 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Smoking; Men; Topkapi Palace; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Fountains; Arabic Calligraphy; Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Palaces; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Two men holding guns on the banks of the Jordan River. 21.7 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1910 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Palestine; Rivers; Outdoors; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jordan River; Regional/National Dress; Guns; Outdoors; Group Portraits; Men
- The Jordan River with a man standing in a rowboat on the bank. 28 x 35.7 cm, Circa 1910 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Outdoors; Boats/Ships; Rivers; Jordan River; Jordan
- Man in national dress standing on the banks of the Jordan river. 27.8 x 35.8 cm, Circa 1910 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Outdoors; Dead Sea; Rivers; Horses; Canes/Walking Sticks; Guns; Regional/National Dress; Jordan River; Jordan; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Animals; Weapons
- Man sitting by the Dead Sea beside a group of branches stacked in a pyramid for a fire. 28 x 36 cm, Circa 1910 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Dead Sea; Hats; Men; Palestine; Water
- View of Jericho from a distance with animals grazing in the foreground. 27.9 x 35.9 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Landscapes; Animals; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jericho; Outdoors; Palestine; Sheep; Bridges; English Writing; French Writing
- View of a river at the bottom of a rocky valley with a stone walkway built on the bank, a stone bridge in the middle-distance and a road built to the right. 27.8 x 35.1 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Turkey; Bridges; Streets/Roads; Rivers; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Outdoors; Landscapes
- Egyptian woman wearing a hijab and niqab. 35.5 x 27.9 cm, Circa 1895 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Women; Individual Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Turkey; Niqab/Burqa; Studio Photography; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; English Writing
- Fountain (sebil) of Sultan Ahmed III in the square outside the Topaki Palace. On reverse side of ref294. 30.3 x 40.5 cm, Circa 1860-1890; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Fountains; Architecture; Topkapi Palace; Palaces; Kiosks/Kushk; Tiles
- Tomb of Sultan Mahmud II. On reverse side of ref293. 30.3 x 40.5 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Tombs/Mausoleums; Architecture; Buildings; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Tomb of Sultan Mahmud II and Abdulaziz; Istanbul, Turkey; Religious Sites
- Entrance to Yedikule Fortress with a few men sitting outside the gate smoking nargiles (181. Porte des Sept Tours). 29 x 38 cm, Circa 1860 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Smoking; Forts/Castles; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; French Writing
- Suleymaniye Mosque as seen from the Beyazit Tower. 28.5 x 36.8 cm, Circa 1880 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Architecture; Religious Sites; Bosphorus; Mosques; Istanbul, Turkey; Suleymaniye Mosque; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Landscapes; French Writing
- Gate to Kucuksu Palace, on the reverse side of ref298. (41. Kiosque du Sultan aux Eaux douces d'Asie). 27.4 x 36 cm, Circa 1870 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Architecture; Istanbul, Turkey; Kucuksu Palace; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Weapons; Palaces; Buildings; French Writing
- Interior of the Hagia Sophia, Istanbul, Turkey. On the reverse side of ref297. 27.4 x 36 cm, Circa 1870 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Arabic Calligraphy; Hagia Sophia; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Religious Sites; French Writing
- View of the Dome of the Rock and Al-Aqsa Mosque on the Temple Mount, Jerusalem. 30.3 x 40.5 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Jerusalem; Religious Sites; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Architecture; Turkish Writing; Mosques; Al-Aqsa Mosque/al-Masjid al-ʾAqṣā; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Palestine; Ottoman Writing; Landscapes
- Arial view of Bursa, Turkey with the Grand Mosque of Bursa (Ulucami) on the right. 30.6 x 40 cm, 1870 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Architecture; Bursa, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Grand Mosque of Bursa; Religious Sites; Landscapes; French Writing
- Group photo of Ottoman soldiers in military uniforms holding gloves and swords. Addressing Sehzade Nurettin Efendi (1901-1944, son of Abdulhamit II) with the signature of Mulazim-i sani (second lieutenant) Nureddin (Nureddin Ibrahim Konyar, 1873 - 1932)." 27.8 x 38 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Swords/Knives; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Bruck, Austria; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Military/Soldiers; Gloves; Facial Hair; Weapons; Fez/Tarboush; Medals/Insignia; Turkish Writing; Hats
- "Crocodile a Port-Said" A German ship flying the German Empire flag docked in Port Said, Egypt. 27.8 x 35.1 cm, Ca. 1870 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Boats/Ships; Men; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Ports; Transportation; Lighthouses; Military/Soldiers; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing
- Statue of Ibrahim Pasha in Cairo (N. 357, Cairo - Statue d'Ibrahaim Pacha). 35.8 x 28 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Men; Pasha; Cairo, Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Street Lamps; Ibrahim, Pasha, 1789-1848
- Egyptian woman looking off to the right in a hijab and an ornamented veil. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Turkey; Head Covers/Veils; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Women
- Al Sayeda Zeinab Mosque in Cairo, Egypt. 27.7 x 21.3 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Religious Sites; Al Sayeda Zeinab Mosque; Mosques; Women; Men; Animals; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Donkeys
- On the left, an ironclad ship with three masts; on the right, two more ships, all docked in Port Said, Egypt. 20.5 x 27 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Men; Lighthouses; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Boats/Ships; Military/Soldiers; French Writing
- Woman reclining on a chair, a shisha pipe hose in hand, slippered feet resting on two stacked cushions. On a table to the right there is a teacup and saucer and a shisha pipe. On reverse side of ref308. 23.6 x 29.9 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Individual Portraits; Egypt; Tea/Coffee; Jewelry; Carpets/Rugs; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Women; Smoking; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles
- Woman looking off to the left, wearing a sheer, light-colored veil. Her hands, each with a ring, are crossed on a railing in front of her. On reverse side of ref307. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Individual Portraits; Egypt; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Painted Backdrops; Jewelry; Women
- Woman wearing a niqab, carrying a naked child on her shoulder. On reverse side of ref310. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Furnishings; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Children; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Niqab/Burqa
- Arab woman holding a tarabuk, and a shisha (hookah) pipe on a small table with mother-of-pearl inlay sits to the left. On reverse side of ref309. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Singing/Singers; Women; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Musical Instruments; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Furnishings; Smoking; Egypt
- Woman in national dress on top of a saddled donkey. The donkey wears a adorned chain around its neck and a servant with a crop stands to the rear of the donkey. On reverse side of ref312. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egypt; Jewelry; Animals; Donkeys; Regional/National Dress; Women; Group Portraits; French Writing; Turbans
- Two women, one standing, holding a two-handled pot on her head and one crouching, her left hand resting on a piece of pottery. On reverse side of ref311. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Pottery; Doors/Entrances; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jewelry; Women; Group Portraits
- Smiling woman, holding her dark colored veil across her body with her right hand. On reverse side of ref314. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Egypt; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Women; Individual Portraits; Head Covers/Veils
- Woman in national dress with hijab and a niqab. The woman carries a naked child on her left shoulder, the child's head resting on hers. On reverse side of ref313. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Egypt; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Children; Regional/National Dress; Women
- Woman with flowers in her hair in a long light-colored dress with floral embroidery. 29.4 x 19.5 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Embroidery; Women; Furnishings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Individual Portraits; French Writing
- 427 - Danseuse (Egyptian dancer). 30 x 23.7 cm, Circa 1885-1900 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Belly Dancers; Regional/National Dress; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Individual Portraits; Women; Cairo, Egypt; Dancing
- 30? - A woman leaning on a clay urn, posing against a painted backdrop. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Painted Backdrops; Turkey; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Regional/National Dress; Women; Head Covers/Veils
- 1116 - A studio portrait of two bare-breasted women seated together. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Group Portraits; Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Jewelry; Regional/National Dress; Women; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Nude/Naked
- A woman holding a baby in her lap, wearing a loose veil and beaded necklace. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Jewelry; Children; Women; Group Portraits; French Writing
- A woman wearing an ornate face veil. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Niqab/Burqa; Head Covers/Veils; Individual Portraits; Women; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egypt; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils
- An vendor of sugarcane, a man with a waterskin and a girl leaning out of the mashrabiya. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, Circa 1890 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Street Vendors; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egypt
- A studio portrait of a man with a mustache and beard, wearing glasses. 29.7 x 23.6 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Men
- A river with a stone bridge crossing it and mountains in the background. 27.1 x 33.0 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Turkey; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Bridges; Rivers; Water; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Ottoman Writing
- A group of women and men sit around a restaurant table, others look on from a window in the background. 27.7 x 33.5 cm, Circa 1930-1932 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Group Portraits; Restaurants/bars; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Istanbul, Turkey; Hats; Drinks/Beverages; Flags; Food; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; French Writing
- A row of Corinthian columns supporting arches (linked ref332 and ref333). 27.8 x 35.2 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Unknown Locations; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- A view of a stucco ceiling, lined by Corinthian columns (linked ref331 and ref333). 35.3 x 27.8 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Unknown Locations
- A colonnade of Corinthian columns at the edge of a temple (linked ref331 and ref332). 27.9 x 35.2 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
- The ruins of a basilica. 28.0 x 35.1 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Unknown Locations; Churches; Architecture; Religious Sites
- 224 - Mosque of Omar. Omar Moschee. Mosquee d'Omar (Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah). 27.9 x 36.1 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Palestine; Jerusalem; Architecture; Religious Sites; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; German Writing; French Writing; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Buildings
- Ruins of a temple with Corinthian columns. 27.9 x 35.1 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Temples; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Unknown Locations; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- 109 - Le Fort Pharos (Citadel of Qaitbay). 27.9 x 35.2 cm, Circa 1870-1889 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mediterranean Sea; Buildings; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Forts/Castles; Alexandria, Egypt; French Writing
- Cyprus, Famagosta (Porta da Mar, Famagusta, marble from the ancient town of Salamis, inscription dated 1496). 35.2 x 27.9 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Cyprus; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Forts/Castles; Forts/Castles; Famagusta, Cyprus
- A studio portrait of a baby propped up on a rattan chair. 10.3 x 6.5 cm, Circa 1860-1870 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Greece; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Children; Greek Writing; Ottoman Writing; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- A studio portrait of a girl wearing button-up boots. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Girls; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Kadikoy, Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Children
- A studio portrait of a girl wearing a dress with a lace collar. 10.4 x 6.5 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Children; Girls
- A studio portrait of a young man wearing a double-breasted uniform with brass buttons. 10.2 x 6.3 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Uniforms; Fez/Tarboush; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Hats
- A studio portrait of a woman a coat with asymmetric fastening (same image as ref344). 10.5 x 6.8 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Women
- A studio portrait of a woman a coat with asymmetric fastening (same image as ref343). 10.5 x 6.8 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Women
- A studio portrait of a man wearing a military uniform and glasses, text on reverse "artillery lieutenant". 11.0 x 7.0 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Swords/Knives; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Hats; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Individual Portraits; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Edirne, Turkey; Turkish Writing; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Weapons
- A young woman looking off-camera, wearing a blouse with an embroidered collar. 13.8 x 8.9 cm, January 1913 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Women; German Writing; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
- A studio portrait of a man wearing a three-piece suit and glasses. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Individual Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Men; Studio Photography; Istanbul, Turkey; Signatures; Facial Hair; Greek Writing
- A portrait of a man wearing a uniform and a young girl. 16.4 x 10.6 cm, Undated; G. Glikeas (Glykias), Phener Rue Balat, Sokak Apti Sou-Bashi no. 15, Constantinople (Fener, Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey; Balat, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Fez/Tarboush; Girls; Children; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; French Writing; Hats
- A food vendor by the banks of the Bosphorus. 14.4 x 18.7 cm, Circa 1896 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dogs; Animals; Cattle/Cows; Street Vendors; Bosphorus; Boats/Ships; Umbrellas/Parasols; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Food; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Women; Men; Buildings; Facial Hair; Transportation; Water
- Four men standing in front of a steam locomotive, with a shoreline running alongside the tracks. 19.0 x 25.2 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Men; Railways; Trains; Coast; Uniforms; Transportation; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Hats
- Complex of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaytbay and the surrounding Northern Cemetery (City of the Dead). 21.2 x 27.1 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Tombs/Mausoleums; Cemeteries; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; Mosque and Tomb of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaitbay; Mosques; Men; Religious Sites; Landscapes
- A studio portrait of a man with two young girls, one wears a dress with an anchor motif. 17.5 x 10.5 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Children; Girls; Men; Cairo, Egypt; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- A studio portrait of a woman leaning on an ornate chair. 21.0 x 10.9 cm, Circa 1910 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Women; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- The 'shadırvan' (ablution fountain) of the Yeni Cami (New Mosque). 21.1 x 27.0 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; New Mosque / Yeni Cami; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; New Mosque / Yeni Cami; Architecture; Mosques; Religious Sites; Fountains; Turkish Writing
- The military barracks and coastline of Izmir. 19.7 x 25.6 cm, Circa 1890 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Landscapes; Aegean Sea; Boats/Ships; Izmir, Turkey; Smyrna; Military/Soldiers; French Writing
- Constantinople, Tombeaux des Sultans Mahmoud II et Adb-ul-Aziz (Istanbul, Tombs of Sultans Mahmud II and Abdulaziz, interior view). 20.6 x 26.2 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Tombs/Mausoleums; Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey; Tomb of Sultan Mahmud II and Abdulaziz; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Praying; Quran/Koran; Religious Sites; Individual Portraits; French Writing
- Two bridges, one with a static steam locomotive on it. 19.0 x 25.4 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)